Guide to the Ayun Halliday Papers, 1990-2015 RL.11289
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Ayun Halliday papers
1990-2015
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Halliday, Ayun
RL.11289
11 Linear Feet 18 boxes
Ayun Halliday is an American writer and actress. Her works center primarily on the areas of motherhood, travel, and women's social issues. The Ayun Halliday Papers contain her writings including books, plays, and the zine East Village Inky; as well as correspondence and ephemera related to her publications; zines by others and artwork.
11.0 linear feet
Arrangement
The first three series (Correspondence, Grants and Awards and Workshops and Speaking Engagements) are arranged chronologically by year.
All subsequent series including writings and works by both Halliday and others are arranged alphabetically by title.
Content Description
The Ayun Halliday Papers are arranged into the following nine series: Correspondence, Grants and Awards, Workshops and speaking engagements, Writings-Books, Writings-Plays, Writings-Zines, Writings-Other Publications, Mail Art Publications (by others), and Zines by Others.
The first seven of these series comprise Halliday's personal writings and works including books, plays, artwork and the zine East Village Inky. The collection also includes correspondence and ephemera related to her publications, as well as items associated with workshops and speaking engagements given by Halliday about underground press publications, female travel, autobiographical writing and other topics.
The final two series represent more than 200 zines and works Halliday collected from others artists obtained primarily through trade with other creators. These publications span a wide range of subjects intended for both adults and children including feminism, motherhood, child rearing, New York City, zines, art, music, travel, food and cooking, body image and consciousness, sexual education, and more.
Biographical / Historical
Ayun Halliday is a writer and actress born in Indianapolis, Indiana. She studied at the Park Tudor School and received her degree in Theater Performance from Northwestern University. She is an avid traveler who began writing plays for her experimental theater group in Chicago, the Neo-Futurists, in 1988. It was there that she met her husband, Greg Kotis, a playwright best known for the musical Urinetown.
In addition to her travel writing, she is best known as the author and illustrator of the zine East Village Inky, a publication that she named after her home in New York City's East Village and her first daughter India (nicknamed "Inky"). The zine is autobiographical, and her family features prominently in many of the issues. The success of this zine led to a contract with Bust magazine writing for the Mother Superior Column on parenting in 2007.
Halliday's other published writing includes a young adult graphic novel, a children's book, a collection of short stories and a cookbook illustrated with non-food related images. She is also the proprietor of the popular food blog Dirty Sugar Cookies.
Halliday currently lives with her husband in Brooklyn.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Ayun Halliday papers were received as a gift by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library in 2016.
Motherhood--United States; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture
- Correspondence, 1998-2013; 6 boxes
  - Correspondence, 1998-2000 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 2001 (Box 1-2)
  - Correspondence, 2002 (Box 3-4)
  - Correspondence, 2003 (Box 4-5)
  - Correspondence, 2004-2006 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, 2010-2013 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, bookstores and distributors (Box 6)
- Grants and Awards, 1999-2009; 1 boxes
  - Center for Book Arts application, 2009 (Box 6)
  - New York Foundation for the Arts application, 1999 (Box 6)
  - Firecracker Alternative Book Award, 2002 (Box 6)
  - Utne Independent Press Award nomination, 2005 (Box 6)
  - Wales Literary Agency (Box 6)
  - Welcome Hill Studios (Box 6)
  - Zine Culture Syllabus, 2003 (Box 6)
- Workshops and speaking engagements, 1 boxes
  - Third Grade Zine Workshop (Box 6)
  - Unsavvy Traveller (Box 6)
  - A Woman Alone (Box 6)
  - Western Carolina Literary Festival (Box 6)
  - Zine Workshop Handouts (Box 6)
- Writings, 2 boxes
  - Books
    - The Big Rumpus manuscript (3 folders) (Box 7)
    - The Big Rumpus manuscript (3 folders) (Box 7)
    - Dirty Sugar Cookies (Box 7)
    - Job Hopper, uncorrected proof (Box 7)
    - Neonatal Sweet Potato (Box 7)
    - Neonatal Sweet Potato, artwork (Box 7)
    - No Touch Monkey, uncorrected proof (Box 8)
    - Peanut, advanced reader's copy (Box 8)
    - Zinesters Guide to NYC, artwork (Box 8)
  - Plays
    - Bagel (Box 8)
    - Big Goddess Powwow; Them Bones (Box 8)
    - Edenweed, 1987 (Box 8)
    - Fawnbook postcard (Box 8)
    - Janis Joplin's Kosmic Kousin (Box 8)
  - Zines
    - East Village Inky drawing slides (Box 9)
    - East Village Inky, Issues 10-11, 13, 16-19 (Box 9)
    - East Village Inky, Issues 20-27, 29 (Box 9)
    - East Village Inky, Issues 30-39 (Box 9)
    - East Village Inky, Issues 40-48, 55 (Box 9)
    - East Village Inky Bingo Game (Box 9)
    - East Village Inky Bingo Game (Box 9)
    - Mix It Up Funky with India's Birthday Coloring Book, 2001 (Box 9)
    - Reviews and articles (Box 9)
    - East Village Inky, 340 sq ft apartment issue (Box 9)
    - East Village Inky: Back issues synopsis and subject index (Box 9)
    - Scavenger zine (Box 10)
    - Bathtub Fortune Cookie Fan zine (Box 10)
    - Massage Therapy zine (Box 10)
    - Nature Coloring Book (Box 10)
    - Zine-related audio CDs (Box 10)
    - Zine-related buttons (Box 10)
  - Other publications
    - My Life in Zines (Box 10)
    - Rag magazine (Box 10)
    - Hip Mama (Box 10)
    - Mama Calendar, 2005-2014 (Box 10)
- Mail Art Publications by Others, 1 boxes
  - Mail art related materials (Box 10)
  - Action Resource Guide (ARG) Cata-zine, by Ashley Parker Owens (Box 10)
  - AIDS International Mail Art (Box 10)
  - Eraser Carvers Quarterly (Box 10)
  - FACE (Femail Art Network) (Box 10)
  - Global Mail (Box 10)
  - Going Postal (Box 10)
  - Lime Green News (Box 10)
  - Netshaker (Box 10)
  - Red Letter Day (Box 10)
- Zines by Others, 8 boxes
  - L'abecedaire de Chat/The ABC of CAt (Box 11)
  - 2013 ABQ Zine Games: Zine Trivia Challenge (Box 11)
  - A to Z in the Monstrous Manual (Box 11)
  - Aleister Crowley Fan Club Newsletter (Box 11)
  - All on Black (Box 11)
  - Ambivalence (Box 11)
  - Amusing Yourself to Death (Box 11)
  - Amusing Yourself to Death (Box 11)
  - Animal Feelings (Box 11)
  - Annus Horribilis (Box 11)
  - Anywhere I Lay My Head (Box 11)
  - Atlas of Childhood (Box 11)
  - Aubrey's Lego Club (Box 11)
  - The Avocado (Box 11)
  - Bar Scrawl (Box 11)
  - A Beautiful Final Tribute (Box 11)
  - Big Pinch World (Box 11)
  - Biji (Box 11)
  - Bind/Mend/Discard- Brooklyn College Library Zine Collection (Box 11)
  - Birdsong (Box 11)
  - Book of Sick (Box 11)
  - Border Lands (Box 11)
  - The Borough is My Library (Box 11)
  - Brainscan (Box 11)
  - Brooklyn (Box 11)
  - Burn Collector (Box 11)
  - Butterfly and Mantis (Box 11)
  - Caboose (Box 12)
  - Carl's Large Story (Box 12)
  - Catbird (Box 12)
  - Chicago Zine Fest 2012 (Box 12)
  - Childlike Empress (Box 12)
  - Chin Music (Box 12)
  - Chinese Sweatshop (Box 12)
  - CLWN WR 45 (Box 12)
  - Crappy Comics (Box 12)
  - D.V. (Box 12)
  - DADAzine (Box 12)
  - Damp Laundry (Box 12)
  - Death Adventure (Box 12)
  - Destination DIY (Box 12)
  - Dilettantes and Heartless Manipulators (Box 12)
  - DIY Zine Libraries (Box 12)
  - Don't Change (Box 12)
  - The Drawing Stick (Box 12)
  - Dust Bunnie (Box 12)
  - Dust Dances in Sunlight (Box 12)
  - Egg Egg (Box 12)
  - Escape from Cybrokryptia (Box 12)
  - Extranjero (Box 12)
  - Fact Sheet Five (Box 12)
  - Faerie (Box 12)
  - Feminist Collections- NWSA Zine, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Fig. 1 Human Body (Box 13)
  - flickr'd out (Box 13)
  - From Oranges to the Big Apple (Box 13)
  - Freaks, Geeks, and Pipsqueaks (Box 13)
  - Frooty Booty (Box 13)
  - The Future Generation (Box 13)
  - Fvck the Media (Box 13)
  - Geraniums and Bacon (Box 13)
  - Getting There (Box 13)
  - Glossolalia (Box 13)
  - God Save the Zine (Box 13)
  - Good Morning You (Box 13)
  - The Great White Honkey Visits South Korea (Box 13)
  - Guide to Being Alone (Box 13)
  - Guide to Dating Gangsters (Box 13)
  - Hag Rag (Box 13)
  - Haiku a Day (Box 13)
  - Hip Mama (Box 13)
  - Hogwarts Camp FAQ (Box 13)
  - Homezine (Box 13)
  - Homos in Herstory (Box 13)
  - Hot Dinner Special (Box 13)
  - An Hour From Now (Box 13)
  - How 2 Zine (Box 13)
  - I am bureaucrat (Box 13)
  - I Dreamed I Was Assertive (Box 13)
  - Illuminated Cold (Box 13)
  - I'm Johnny and I Don't Give a Fuck (Box 14)
  - I'm Not Here to Be Young: The CBGB Adventures (Box 14)
  - Itchy Tits (Box 14)
  - It's All in the Cards (Box 14)
  - It's Captain Elvis' Coloring and Activity Book (Box 14)
  - It's Time to Make a Zine (Box 14)
  - "Jam" Sketchbook (Box 14)
  - Jargon (Box 14)
  - Jen(ny) Ambular (Box 14)
  - Jesus Loves Me (Box 14)
  - Juitchy (Box 14)
  - Junk Drawer (Box 14)
  - Jutchy Yaya (Box 14)
  - The Ken Chronicles (Box 14)
  - The King, the Jester, the Princess, the Dragon, and Jay-Z (Box 14)
  - Late Night Thinking (Box 14)
  - The Legend of Brunhild (Box 14)
  - Leeking Ink (Box 14)
  - Lessons in Taxidermy (Box 14)
  - Let Gluten Freedom Ring (Box 14)
  - Life Story (Box 14)
  - Limited Delivery Area (Box 14)
  - A Little Book of Haiku (Box 14)
  - Los Angeles Zine Fest (Box 14)
  - Low Hug (Box 14)
  - Lower East Side Librarian (Box 14)
  - Lucky (Box 14)
  - Luna in Tuna (Box 14)
  - Mama Gathering 2003 (Box 15)
  - Mechanism Exploded (Box 15)
  - Minder (Box 15)
  - Modicum (Box 15)
  - Moment's Notice (Box 15)
  - The Murky Realm (Box 15)
  - My Little Friend (Box 15)
  - The Nasty Oh-Dear (Box 15)
  - ND (Box 15)
  - Not A.True Story (Box 15)
  - Notes and Bolts: A Compendium of Music, Food and Art (Box 15)
  - The Obsesser (Box 15)
  - Once Upon a Photobooth (Box 15)
  - One Story (Box 15)
  - The Oubliette (Box 15)
  - Pander Zine Distro Catalogue (Box 15)
  - Papercutter (Box 15)
  - Pennamite (Box 15)
  - The Pen-sill-vain-ya Lottaree (Box 15)
  - Pep G!rlz (Box 15)
  - The Perfect Mix Tape Segue (Box 15)
  - Picaflor (Box 15)
  - Pieces: Short Works by Shanyna Marchese (Box 15)
  - Pink Tea (Box 15)
  - Placenta (Box 15)
  - Poisonous Plants in the Garden (Box 15)
  - The Poor Little Princess (Box 15)
  - Power Candy (Box 15)
  - Public Streets, Corporate Power (Box 15)
  - Pushing Pencils Comic Zine (Box 15)
  - Rabid Rabbit (Box 16)
  - Rag Hag (Box 16)
  - Rigor Mortis (Box 16)
  - Riverside Art Scene (Box 16)
  - Rochester Teen Set (Box 16)
  - Rock On! A Pocket Guide to Some Rockin' Venues of NYC's Past... (Box 16)
  - Roots and Wings (Box 16)
  - Runner Runner (Box 16)
  - Scribble Faster (Box 16)
  - Scribbles and Scratches (Box 16)
  - Seaglass (Box 16)
  - Secondhand Emotion (Box 16)
  - Shards of Glass in Your Eye (Box 16)
  - Shojo Beat (Box 16)
  - Sketchbooks-Mostly Travel (Box 16)
  - Silkscreen (Box 16)
  - Simple Routines (Box 16)
  - Slave to the Needles (Box 16)
  - Slug & Lettuce (Box 16)
  - Small Science Collective Zines (Box 16)
  - So Tough (Box 16)
  - Some Like it Hot Cookbook (Box 16)
  - Spaz (Box 16)
  - The Story of {Open} (Box 17)
  - Stretch Mark (Box 17)
  - Super City (Box 17)
  - Syndicate Product (Box 17)
  - The SysTris Reader (Box 17)
  - Tales to Behold (Box 17)
  - Tazewell's Favorite Eccentric (Box 17)
  - My Teenage Robot Life (Box 17)
  - Tenacious: Art and Writings from Women in Prison (Box 17)
  - Thanks Mom (Box 17)
  - That Olde, Weird America (Box 17)
  - There is No Such Thing As (Box 17)
  - Thinger Dingers (Box 17)
  - Time Enough At Last (Box 17)
  - Time's Up! (Box 17)
  - Tonight and Every Night (Box 17)
  - The Transmitter (Box 17)
  - Trickhips (Box 17)
  - Trigger (Box 17)
  - True Fiction (Box 17)
  - True Tales of the World's Worst Teaching Assistants (Box 17)
  - Twilight Reflections on an Ethically Raised Life (Box 17)
  - Usual Tapes (Box 17)
  - Vietnamania (Box 17)
  - Wag (Box 17)
  - A Wave Has Hit Again (Box 17)
  - We'll Never Have Paris (Box 17)
  - The Wet Firecracker (Box 17)
  - What is this? (Box 17)
  - What's the Word? (Box 18)
  - White Elephants (Box 18)
  - Whoosh: the Zine for Whale Lovers (Box 18)
  - Winona Ryder/Rydehair (Box 18)
  - Women Got Me Drinking (Box 18)
  - Work is Where the Heart Is (Box 18)
  - Worries: Ridiculous Crap the Makes Me Anxious (Box 18)
  - Wow, Can I eat it all? (Box 18)
  - Writerman (Box 18)
  - Writing and Loss (Box 18)
  - Wronka Bros. (Box 18)
  - Xerography Debt (Box 18)
  - Xtra Tuf 6.75: Report from Uyak Bay (Audio Zine) (Box 18)
  - You Can Work Any Hundred Hours a Week You Want (in your underwear)!! A History of Micropublishing (Box 18)
  - You Can't Shut Up: Finding a Voice in Women's Zines (Box 18)
  - Your Name Here (Box 18)
  - Zine Libs (Box 18)
  - Zineorama Periodicals and Books (Box 18)
  - Zine World (Box 18)
  - Zombie Cat (Box 18)
  - Zuzu and the Baby Catcher (Box 18)